ICICI LBRD Elevat and Tata AIG Micare
Sector both are very comprehensive
health insurance plans.  If you are
confused between these two plans, then
all your confusion will be cleared in today's video.
I have done a detailed comparison of both the plans on the basis of their features,
benefits, claim analysis and premium.
After watching this video, you will be
able to decide which plan
is more suitable for you.  Hello friends,
I am Ashutosh, your personal finance coach.
Let's start the video.  ICICI LBD
and Tata AIG are both full-fledged general
insurance companies that operate in almost all
general insurance verticals.
Apart from health insurance, the
services of full-fledged general insurance companies are more effective than stand-alone health insurance companies because
their business is also quite big and their
profitability is also good.  Talking about the
minimum and maximum entry age of both the plans, the
minimum entry age is 18
years and the maximum is no entry age.  You can
enter at any age.
Senior citizens can also take it.  Dependent
children are covered after 90 days.  Sum
Assured Option ICICI LBARD Elevate has 5
lakh to 3 crore sum assured option.
Apart from that, there is also an option of unlimited sum assured.
Tata IG Medical Premier has a
sum assured option of Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 lakh.  It
is available.  You can remove this capping with
Single Private AC Room and Room Modifier in room category ICICI lambda Deliverat.
Tata AIG Medic Premier also has a
capping of single private room.
With a rider you can remove this too.
AYUSH treatment Ayurvedic Unani
Siddha Homeopathy which is an alternative treatment.
Up to sum assured is covered in both the plans.
Pre and post hospitalization is
for 90 days and 180 days in Elevate.
Medicare Select covers 90 days and post-
hospitalization coverage for 90 days.  This is quite
less which should be at least 180 days.
Day Care Treatment
All day care treatments are covered up to the sum assured in both the plans.
Day treatments are treatments
that do
not require 24-hour hospitalization.   This is done
in a few hours procedure.
Organ donor cover up to sum assured is available
in both the plans.  Domestic hospitalization
is also covered up to sum assured.  Domestic
hospitalizations are those hospitalizations
that we get done at home.  Home Care
Treatment Elevate offers the option of nursing at home for
a few days.
Not in Medical Select.  Road ambulance
up to sum assured is covered in both the plans.
But there is a camping in Meic that is just
50 km.  Road
ambulance is available to you only within a radius of .  Air ambulance
is available as an add-on.  ICIC is
not applicable in Medical Select in Elvet.  Free
health checkup is available as an add-on in both the plans.  There is
no free health checkup.
Modern treatment is covered
up to sum assured in both the plans in both the variants.  There
is no capping.  Second
Medical Opinion Second medical opinion is
not available in both the plans.  E-
consultation is available as an add-on.  E
is not available in Medical Select at Elevate.  Maternity cover is available in both the plans.
After 2 years of waiting
period where 10% of sum assured
maximum up to Rs 1 lakh is available in Elevate.  Similarly,
coverage of 10% of sum
assured maximum up to Rs 1 lakh is available in Medical Select.   The
Newborn Baby Cover is part of the maternity at Elevate.
But it is not available in Medical Select.
World wide cover as add on
is available.  Elevate does not have Micare Select.
If you need global cover,
Tata's Micare Premier is quite good.
In case of global cover.  Plan
variants There is also Elevate and Medic
Select, which also has the same variant.  Waiting
Periods: Like all other plans, an
initial waiting period of 30 days, a
specific waiting period of 2 years and a
pre-existing disease waiting period of 3 years will be
available in both the plans.  Talking about its unique
benefits, first of all,
in Elevate we get a 100% bonus
through Lifetime Power Booster and
apart from that there is an inbuilt bonus of 20%.  So
with Power Booster, if you have a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then
in 10 years it will become Rs 1 cr and
in 20 years it will become Rs 2 cr.
Apart from that, the option of infinite care is available.   This
means that you can make a claim for an unlimited amount.
Even if your policy is worth Rs 10 lakh.
You should have a bonus of Rs 10 lakh or Rs 20 lakh.
But a claim of Rs 1 crore also came.  So
you can use it with infinite care.
Apart from that, unlimited restoration for full
and partial related and unrelated
illnesses like lifestyle diseases like
hypertension, diabetes, asthma,
hyperlipidemia, obesity, apart from that
coronary artery disease, PTCA done
priority one year, that is, even
if you have had stenting before one year, you
can still take this plan without waiting period.
Apart from that, two-hour hospitalization
add-on is also available.  No Claim Bonus:
Talking about Tata AIG Medical Select,
instead of cumulative bonus, we
get No Claim Bonus in which
we can withdraw 1% of the premium every year for
every no claim or can get a bonus of 50% of the sum assured
maximum up to 100%.
Apart from that, Restore Infinity Plus means
infinite advantage for unlimited times restoration related and unrelated illnesses.
So, like Elevate's Infinite Care,
we get a claim with no
limit on the sum assured.
Apart from that, there is an early access option in
which if we take a multi-year policy, then
multi-year sum assured is available.
Suppose you take a policy of Rs 10 lakh for 3 years,
then with this rider only a
sum assured of Rs 30 lakh will be available to you.  Apart from that, there is
Super Charge Bonus in which you get a bonus of 100%
to 500% for 5 years.  Advanced Cover
Rider: This is similar to Jump Start,
in which you can get cover for ABCD, Asthma,
Blood Pressure, Cholesterol and Diabetes without any
pre-existing disease waiting
period of
31 days.
Talking about optional covers, ICICI Elevate has
Infinite Care which gives you unlimited sum
assured.  Inflation protector that increases
your basic sum assured according to inflation.
Power Booster
which gives you a 100% bonus every year.
Domestic Air Ambulance Jump Start which
covers you for pre-existing diseases which are lifestyle diseases or ABCD diseases without
waiting period, Dependent Accommodation
Claim Protector which covers non-payable items.
Room
Modifiers upgrade and downgrade your room category.
Compassionate visit,
nursing at home, maternity, newborn,
vaccination, all three are parts of maternity.
Durable Medical Equipment,
Wheelchairs: If any durable
medical equipment is required
after hospitalization, you can use it.
Covalsons Benefit, Health Checkup, Be
Fit This is OPD Rider.  Network Advantage
Some of the preferred networks are ICICI.  If
you take this rider, you
get some discount on the premium.  But you have to
take hospitalization within the same network.  If you
go outside the network, you will have to pay.
We have to avoid personal accidents and critical illnesses.  Teleconsultation
option to reduce maternity waiting period.   There
is a waiting period of 2 years.  With Butt Rider
you can reduce it for a year.
Venture Copayment and NRI
Discount.  Talking about the riders of Tata AG Medical Select,
first there is a waiting period of two years for consumable
benefit, maternity care for non-payable items,
maternity benefit reduction in
maternity care,
but with this rider it can be one year.
Infinite Advantage which
gives you unlimited sum assured for a single claim.
Early Access which is a multi-year policy with
multi-year sum assured available.
Room Category Select Room Category can be upgraded
and downgraded.  You
can opt for Aggregate Deductible
with your policy.  Super Charge Bonus: 500%
bonus Advanced Cover Rider which
covers ABCD diseases without waiting period
Preventive Health Checkup OPD Care
for OPD Apart from this, there is an Emaar Har
rider for female policy holders
which gives you the benefit of additional diagnostic tests for breast cancer and any gynecological
problems.
Apart from that, we get the option of mental well being
in this plan.  Talking about zones,
ICICI Elevate has four zone based
premium and Tata AIG Medical Select has
three zones.  Talking about premium,
for premium I have
taken the example of 35 year old couple with two kids for
10 laird in Delhi NCR.  The
premium of ICICI Elevat is Rs 20,000
while the premium of Medical Select is Rs
27,000 but there are many discounts in it.
After discount this premium becomes much less
and it is comparable to ICICI
Elevat Multi Year Policy. We
get five year policy in ICICI Elevat.  You can take a
maximum three-year policy in Medical Select.
Talking about claim ratios, the
most important is the incurred claim ratio
which is 82% for ICICI Elevat and
76% for Tata AG.  Looking at this ratio, we come to know
that both the plans
are quite consistent in giving claims and are
good in terms of claim settlement.  Claim settlement
ratio is 80% for ICICI and 95% for Tata.
Talking about the complaint ratio, there
are 10,000 claims.  ICICI has 14 complaints and
Tata AIG has 10 complaints.  Ah,
talking about value for money, both are
premium wise fair valued.  Ah, even though
you may feel that Tata's premium
seems a bit high, but premium wise
this company is quite consistent.  There is
no drastic change in your premium.
Based on this comparison, you can select
which of these two plans
is more suitable for you.  If you
need my help in the plan section or
want to buy a policy with me, you can book a consultation with me on the number given below
or by visiting my website AshutoshShukla.com.
Friends, as important as it is to
get health insurance, it is equally important to
get it from the right place.
After sales services play a very important
role in health insurance.  Try to get a policy from a good advisor
who can help you
in making the claim.  If you liked the video,
please like it.  Subscribe to the channel
and let us know in the comments if you want to see a comparison video for any health insurance.  That's all for
today's video, see you
in the next video.  Thank you.